export const miscelaneous_2 = [
    {
        choices: ["Martensite is strong and hard, but brittle, Tampering toughens it and reduces brittleness.", "Tempering of martensite is done by judicious reheating to produce, by diffusion, a fine - grained tough, strong microstructures.", "Martensite is fine grained gamma-ferrite, supersaturated with carbon, in a metastable body centered tetragonal structure. It forms by shear (slippage) during the rapid quench of face centered cubic austenite (gamma-ferrite)", "Bainite and tampered martensite have distinctively different microstructures."],
        correctAnswer: "Bainite and tampered martensite have distinctively different microstructures.",
        question: "All of the following statements about austenite - martensite - bainite transformation in steel are correct, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["the fraction of the total mass that is saturated vapor", "the fraction of the total mass that is saturated liquid", "the fraction of the total volume that is saturated liquid", "the fraction of the total volume that is saturated vapor"],
        correctAnswer: "the fraction of the total mass that is saturated vapor",
        question: "How is the quality, x, of a liquid-vapor mixture defined?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1-T1/T2", "1-(T1/T2)^r", "1-T2/T1", "T1/T2"],
        correctAnswer: "1-T1/T2",
        question: "For a heat engine operating between two temperatures (T2 &amp;amp;gt; T1), what is the maximum efficiency attainable?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Temperature coefficient of expansion and dielectric constant", "Temperature coefficient of expansion and specific heat", "Density and velocity of sound in the material", "Density and inter - atomic spacing in the material"],
        correctAnswer: "Density and velocity of sound in the material",
        question: "Young&amp;amp;#39;s modulus of elasticity for a material can be calculated indirectly from which of the following properties of the material?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Magnetic domains are small volumes existent within a single crystal where atomic magnetic moments are undirectonally aligned", "Domains are randomly oriented when unmagnetized. On magnetization, domains oriented with the external field grow at the expense of unaligned domains.", "Impurities, Inclusions and strain hardening interfere with change of domain boundaries, and add to the permanency of a magnet.", "High magnetic susceptibility of ferromagnetic materials disappears below the Curie temperature."],
        correctAnswer: "High magnetic susceptibility of ferromagnetic materials disappears below the Curie temperature.",
        question: "All of the following statements about ferromagnetism are correct EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Elastic limit to proportional limit", "Unit stress to unit strain", "Shear strain to compressive strain", "Unit lateral deformation to the unit longitudinal deformation."],
        correctAnswer: "Unit lateral deformation to the unit longitudinal deformation.",
        question: "Poisson&amp;amp;#39;s Ratio is the ratio of the",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Ductile fracture is characterized by significant amounts of energy absorption and plastic deformation (evidenced by elongation and reduction in cross-sectional area)", "Ductile - brittle transition in failure mode occurs at reduced temperatures for most materials, because fracture strength remains constant with temperature wihle yield strength increases as temperature is reduced. At high temperatures yield strength is least; at low temperatures fracture strength is least.", "Fatigue failure due to cyclic stress frequently dependent.", "Brittle fracture occurs with little plastic deformation and relatively small energy absorption"],
        correctAnswer: "Fatigue failure due to cyclic stress frequently dependent.",
        question: "All of the following statements about mechanical failure are true, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["germanium", "boron", "nothing", "antimony"],
        correctAnswer: "antimony",
        question: "Intrinsic silicon becomes extrinsically, conducive, with electrons as majority carriers, when doped with which of the following?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Z = (T/To)(Dc/D)", "z = T/To", "z = D/Do", "z = pV/RT"],
        correctAnswer: "z = pV/RT",
        question: "The compressibility factor, z, is used for predicting the behavior of non-ideal gases. How is the compressibility factor defined relative to an ideal gas? (Subscript &amp;amp;quot;c&amp;amp;quot; refers to critical value.)",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["lower equipment costs", "increased turbine work output", "increase efficiency", "increased boiler life"],
        correctAnswer: "increased boiler life",
        question: "Which of the following is not an advantage of a superheated, closed Rankine cycle over an open Rankine cycle?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Both lead and cadmium have a hexagonal close-packed crystal structure.", "Iron can have either a face-centered or a body-centered cubic crystal structure.", "Both copper and aluminum have a face-centered crystal structure.", "Both magnesium and zinc have a hexagonal close-packed crystal structure."],
        correctAnswer: "Both lead and cadmium have a hexagonal close-packed crystal structure.",
        question: "Which of the following statements is false?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["(actual price - std. price) (quantity used)", "(quantity purchased - quantity used)(actual price)", "(quantity purchased x actual price) - (quantity purchased x std. price)", "(quantity issued - std. quantity) (std. price)"],
        correctAnswer: "(quantity purchased x actual price) - (quantity purchased x std. price)",
        question: "How is the material purchase price variances defined?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["bending moment of the beam", "slope of the elastic curve", "tensile strength of beam", "load on the beam"],
        correctAnswer: "load on the beam",
        question: "The differential of the shear equation is which one of the following?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Streamlines spaced to bound streamtubes of equal volume flow rate, Q.", "Flow and pressure drops in distribution systems.", "Equipotential lines perpendicular to streamlines", "Paths of particles in 2 and 3-dimensional flow."],
        correctAnswer: "Flow and pressure drops in distribution systems.",
        question: "Flow nets are drawn to show all of the following EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["irreversible", "isothermal", "isobaric", "reversible"],
        correctAnswer: "reversible",
        question: "For which type of process does the equation dQ = TdS hold?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["WL^2/8", "WL/8", "WL/2", "WL^2/2"],
        correctAnswer: "WL/8",
        question: "The maximum bending moment of a beam simply supported at both ends and subject to a total load W uniformly distributed over its length L is expressed by the formula:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Activation energy for diffusion through structures is inversely proportional to atomic packing factor in the lattice", "Atoms can diffuse both within crystal and across grain (crystal) boundaries", "Diffusion is irreversible and requires and activation energy; Its rate increases exponentially with temperature. It follows the diffusion equation where flux equals diffusivity times concentration gradient", "Vacancies and Interstitial atoms affect diffusion, whose net result is movement of atoms to produce a structure of less strain and of uniform composition"],
        correctAnswer: "Activation energy for diffusion through structures is inversely proportional to atomic packing factor in the lattice",
        question: "All of the following statements about diffusion and grain growth are correct, EXCEPT",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["hg^2 - hf^2", "hf", "hg - hf", "hg"],
        correctAnswer: "hg - hf",
        question: "What is the expression for the heat of vaporization?&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;hg = enthalpy of the saturated vapor&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;hf = enthalpy of the saturated liquid",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Pitting occurs in oxygen - rich anodic areas, and the rust is deposited nearby.", "Contact with water, and oxygen are necessary for rusting to occur", "Contact with a more  electropositive metal reduces rusting.", "Halides aggravate rusting, a process which involves electrochemical oxidation-reduction reactions."],
        correctAnswer: "Pitting occurs in oxygen - rich anodic areas, and the rust is deposited nearby.",
        question: "All of the following statements about rusting of iron are correct, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["32 degrees F and zero pressure", "0 degrees F and zero pressure", "0 degrees C and one atmosphere pressure", "0 K and one atmoshpere pressure"],
        correctAnswer: "0 degrees C and one atmosphere pressure",
        question: "Which of the following is standard temperature and pressure (STP)?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Rankine", "combine Brayton-Rankine", "Brayton", "Carnot"],
        correctAnswer: "Carnot",
        question: "Which of the following thermodynamic cycles is the most efficient?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Increase at the same rate as the area of the metal increases", "decrease at twice the rate as the area of the metal increases", "Increase at twice the rate the area of the metal increases", "decrease at the same rate as the area of the metal increases"],
        correctAnswer: "Increase at the same rate as the area of the metal increases",
        question: "A thin homogeneous metallic plate containing a hole is heated sufficiently to cause expansion. If the coefficient of surface expansion is linear, the area of the hole will:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Yield strength of commercially available heat treated alloy steels does not exceed 200,000 psi", "Intergranular corrosion of chromium - nickel stainless steels is reduced when stabilized by addition of columbium (niobium), titanium or tantalum to preferentially form carbides and prevent chromium depletion and chromium carbide precipitation is grain boundary areas", "Abrasion resistance of extra strength steels may be obtained by increasing by increasing hardness to 225 - 400 Brinell at the expense of some ductility and toughness", "High temperature alloys used in jet engine turbine blades can withstand 2000 degrees F continously over extended periods"],
        correctAnswer: "Yield strength of commercially available heat treated alloy steels does not exceed 200,000 psi",
        question: "All of the following statements about steels are correct, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["cannot be evaluated for brittle materials", "Is the ratio of areas involved in a sudden change of cross section", "is a ratio of the average stress on a section to the allowable stress", "is the ratio of the maximum stress produced in a cross section to the average stress over the section"],
        correctAnswer: "is the ratio of the maximum stress produced in a cross section to the average stress over the section",
        question: "The stress concentration factor",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["forces between electrons and protons", "forces not present in liquids", "primary bonds between atoms", "weak secondary bonds between atoms"],
        correctAnswer: "weak secondary bonds between atoms",
        question: "What are Van der Waals forces?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Specific volume is zero", "Vapor pressure is zero", "Entropy is non-zero", "Internal energy is negative"],
        correctAnswer: "Internal energy is negative",
        question: "Which of the following is true for water at reference temperature where enthalpy is zero?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Sum of the moments of all external forces on one side of the section.", "Sum of the moments of all external forces on both sides of the section", "Sum of the moments of all external forces between supports.", "Difference between the moments on one side of the section and the opposite side."],
        correctAnswer: "Sum of the moments of all external forces on one side of the section.",
        question: "The bending moment at a section of a beam is derived from the",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["only one repeating unit", "small chain lengths", "small side groups", "an atactic configuration of side groups"],
        correctAnswer: "an atactic configuration of side groups",
        question: "Polymers that favor crystallization are least likely to have which of the following?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Air entrained is recommended when concrete is exposed to severe frost action.", "With air entrainment, the quality of water to produce a given consistency (slump) is reduced.", "Air entrainment reduces resistance to the freeze - thaw that occurs when salt is used to melt ice or snow.", "With air entrainment, the quantity of water to produce a specified 28 day compressive strength is reduced."],
        correctAnswer: "Air entrainment reduces resistance to the freeze - thaw that occurs when salt is used to melt ice or snow.",
        question: "All of the following statements about air entrained concrete are correct, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["F = mv^2/R", "F = (mu)N", "F = ma", "F = kx"],
        correctAnswer: "F = kx",
        question: "The relationship between the extension of a spring and the force required to produce the extension is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["PAv", "(Density)AV", "(Density)v^2/P", "DV(Density)/mu"],
        correctAnswer: "PAv",
        question: "Which of the following constitutes a group of parameters with the dimensions of power?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["The coordinates of the unique lattice points for a rhombohedral unit cell are 1/2,1/2,1/2.", "The coordinates of the unique lattice points for a simple cubic unit cell are: 0,0,0; 1/2,1/2,0,1/2,0,1/2; and 0,1/2,1/2.", "The coordinates of the unique lattice points for a simple cubic unit cell are: 0,0,0.", "The coordinates of the unique lattice points for a body-centered cubic unit cell are: 0,0,0 and 1/2,1/2,1/2."],
        correctAnswer: "The coordinates of the unique lattice points for a rhombohedral unit cell are 1/2,1/2,1/2.",
        question: "Which of the following statements is false?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Order - disorder transitions that occur at elevated temperature in solid solutions involve changes due to thermal agitation from preferred orientation to random occupancy of lattice sites", "Solid solutions can result when basic structure of the solvent can accomodate solute additions", "In solid solution larger solute atoms occupy the interstitial space between solvent atoms that are located at the lattice sites", "Solid solutions may result by substition of one atomic species for another, provided radii an electronic structure are compatible"],
        correctAnswer: "In solid solution larger solute atoms occupy the interstitial space between solvent atoms that are located at the lattice sites",
        question: "All of the following statements about solid solution are correct EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["randomness or disorder", "the change in enthalpy of a system", "the internal energy of gas", "the heat capacity of a substance"],
        correctAnswer: "randomness or disorder",
        question: "Entropy is the measure of ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["ft^2/sec", "slugs/sec", "slug sec^2/ft", "sec^2/ft"],
        correctAnswer: "ft^2/sec",
        question: "Kinematics viscosity may be expressed as:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["10", "7", "8", "9"],
        correctAnswer: "9",
        question: "According to the ACI code, the modular ratio, n, of structural concrete with a 28 - day ultimate compressive strength, f&amp;amp;#39;c, of 3000 is nearest to:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Each valence bond may contain up to 2n electrons/n atom; each electron lies at discretely different level.", "Fermi energy level, Ef, is essentially temperature independent, and is the energy at which 50% of available energy states are occupied.", "A conduction bond lies at the next higher set of electronic energy levels above those occupied at the ground state", "Conduction occurs when an electron remains in its existent valence bond."],
        correctAnswer: "Conduction occurs when an electron remains in its existent valence bond.",
        question: "The valence band model used to explain metallic conduction is based on all the following statements, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Assumed to be 1/10 of the 28-day compressive strength.", "Determined by beam tests.", "Neglected.", "Assumed to be 200 psi"],
        correctAnswer: "Neglected.",
        question: "In the design of a reinforced concrete structure, tensile strength of the concrete is normally:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["the magnitude of electrical charge of the protons", "the electrons, particularly the outermost ones", "the weight of the atoms", "the atomic weight expressed in grams per gram-atom"],
        correctAnswer: "the electrons, particularly the outermost ones",
        question: "Which of the following affects most of the electrical and thermal properties of materials?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["(326)", "(623)", "(132)", "(123)"],
        correctAnswer: "(623)",
        question: "A plane intercepts the coordinate axis at x = 1, y = 1, and z = 2. What are the Miller indices of the plane?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["face-centered: (111), body-centered (100)", "face-centered: (100), body-centered (110)", "face-centered: (111), body-centered (110)", "face-centered: (110), body-centered (111)"],
        correctAnswer: "face-centered: (110), body-centered (111)",
        question: "What are the most common slip planes for face-centered cubic and body-centered cubic structures, respectively?&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["h - s", "s - u", "p - T", "p - V"],
        correctAnswer: "h - s",
        question: "On what plane is the Mollier diagram plotted?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["polymers", "isomers", "monomers", "crystal system"],
        correctAnswer: "isomers",
        question: "In molecules of the same composition, what are variations of atomic arrangements known as?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["h = u + P/V", "h = u + pV", "h = u + P/T", "h = pV + T"],
        correctAnswer: "h = u + pV",
        question: "Which of the following relations defines enthalpy?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Stress = E(strain)", "Force/Area = length/change in length", "(Force)(area) = (change in length)/(length)", "Strain = E(stress)"],
        correctAnswer: "Stress = E(strain)",
        question: "Hooke&amp;amp;#39;s Law for an isotropic homogeneous medium experiencing on-dimensional stress is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["can be ignored.", "is infinitely large.", "varies as the velocity squared.", "varies directly as velocity."],
        correctAnswer: "varies directly as velocity.",
        question: "At or below critical velocity in small pipes or at very low velocities, the loss of head due to friction",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["I and III", "III only", "I only", "II only"],
        correctAnswer: "I and III",
        question: "Which of the following accurately describes differences between crystalline polymers and simple crystals?&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;I. Crystalline polymers are made of folded chains of atoms unlike simple crystals.&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;II. Crystal size can be increased by raising the crystallization temperature only in polymers.&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;III. While a simple crystal may be totally crystallized, a polymer can reach only partial crystallization.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Zi/Zi+Zj", "Pi/Pi+Pj", "PiVi/RT", "Ti/Ti+Tj"],
        correctAnswer: "PiVi/RT",
        question: "In an ideal gas mixture of constituents i and j, what is the mole fraction x, equal to?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["More strain hardening requires more time-temperature exposure for relief.", "Strain hardening strengthens metals. Resistance to deformation increases with the amount of strain present.", "Strain hardening is relieved during softening, annealing above the recrystallization temperature.", "Strain hardening is produced by cold working (deformation below the recrystallization temperature)."],
        correctAnswer: "More strain hardening requires more time-temperature exposure for relief.",
        question: "All of the following statements about strain hardening are correct, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["the ionic bond", "the metallic bond", "ionic and metallic bond", "the covalent bond"],
        correctAnswer: "the covalent bond",
        question: "What is the strong bond between hydrogen atoms known as?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["forfeiture", "debt cancellation", "condonation", "liquidated damages"],
        correctAnswer: "condonation",
        question: "Modes of extinguishing obligations when auditor abandons his right to collect:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["It is proportional to length of dislocation, shear modulus, and shortest distance between equivalent lattice sites (points)", "It is caused by generation and movement of dislocatons through shear or plastic deformation", "It is less for sites at grain boundaries than for internal sites within the crystal structure", "It results from trapped vacancies in the crystal lattice"],
        correctAnswer: "It is less for sites at grain boundaries than for internal sites within the crystal structure",
        question: "All of the following statements about strain energy are correct EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.52", "1.00", "0.48", "1.05"],
        correctAnswer: "0.52",
        question: "What is the atomic packing factor for a simple cubic crystal?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Average moment between the two point", "Total shear beyond the two points", "Change in moment between the two points", "Change in shear between the two points"],
        correctAnswer: "Change in moment between the two points",
        question: "The area of the shear diagram of a beam between any two points on the beam is equal to the:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["absolute volume of cement", "water-cement ratio", "sand-gravel", "aggregate gradation"],
        correctAnswer: "water-cement ratio",
        question: "Compressive strength of fully cured concrete is most directly related to:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Ease of slippage is directly related to number of low energy slip planes existent in the lattice structure", "It involves only a few atoms at a time in a series of small disclocation movements", "Slip, or shear along crystal planes, results in an irreversible plastic deformation or permanent set", "Slip planes lie in the direction of the longest distance between neighboring sites in the crystal lattice"],
        correctAnswer: "Slip planes lie in the direction of the longest distance between neighboring sites in the crystal lattice",
        question: "All the following statements about slip are correct, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Density and shear stress", "Shear stress and angular deformation rate", "Density and angular deformation rate", "Density, shear stress and angular deformation rate"],
        correctAnswer: "Shear stress and angular deformation rate",
        question: "Absolute viscosity of a fluid varies with pressure and temperature and is defined as a function of",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["At a distance of about 10% of the orifice diameter upstream from the plane of the orifice.", "At a distance equal to about one-half the orifice diameter downstream from the plane of the orifice.", "At the geometric center of the orifice.", "At a distance equal to about two orifice diameters downstream from the plane of the orifice."],
        correctAnswer: "At a distance equal to about one-half the orifice diameter downstream from the plane of the orifice.",
        question: "The vena contracta of a sharp hydraulic orifice usually occurs:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["The determination of capacity of a material", "The determination of the modulus of toughness", "The determination of the capability of a material for being shaped", "Stress - strain relationships where stresses are applied in more than one direction"],
        correctAnswer: "Stress - strain relationships where stresses are applied in more than one direction",
        question: "Poisson&amp;amp;#39;s ratio is principally used in:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["The moment of Inertia of a large area is equal to the summation of the inertia of the smaller areas within the large area.", "t = (integral) d^2 (dA)", "The area moment of inertia arises whenever the magnitude of the surface forces varies linearly with distance.", "The area closest to the axis of interest are the most significant."],
        correctAnswer: "The area closest to the axis of interest are the most significant.",
        question: "Which statement about area moments of inertia is false?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["WL/2(pi)D^2E", "2WLE/(pi)D^2", "2WL/(pi)D^2E", "WL/(pi)D^2E"],
        correctAnswer: "2WL/(pi)D^2E",
        question: "A homogeneous round bar of diameter D, length L, and total weight W is hung vertically from one end. If E is the modulus of elasticity, what is the total elongation of the bar?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["(delta)Ssurroundings + (delta)Ssystem &amp;amp;lt; or equal to 0", "(delta)Ssurroundings + (delta)Ssystem &amp;amp;lt; 0", "(delta)Ssurroundings + (delta)Ssystem &amp;amp;gt; 0", "(delta)Ssurroundings + (delta)Ssystem &amp;amp;gt; or equal to 0"],
        correctAnswer: "(delta)Ssurroundings + (delta)Ssystem &amp;amp;gt; or equal to 0",
        question: "Which of the following is true for any process?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["the strength will decrease", "the water/cement ratio must be reduced from 10 - 15%", "the strength will increase", "the strength will not be affected"],
        correctAnswer: "the water/cement ratio must be reduced from 10 - 15%",
        question: "When an air entrainment agent is introduced into a concrete mix:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["perpetual inventory system", "periodic inventory system", "cost of good sold", "physical inventory system"],
        correctAnswer: "cost of good sold",
        question: "The difference between the starting and the ending inventory valuations, a term that represents an inventory account adjust is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["The modulus of elasticity of the material", "The length of the column", "The compressive strength of the material", "The radius of gyration of the column"],
        correctAnswer: "The length of the column",
        question: "In a long column (slenderness ratio &amp;amp;gt; 160 which of the following has the greatest influence on its tendency to buckle under a compressive load.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["ultrasonic", "radiography", "chemical analysis", "magnetic particle"],
        correctAnswer: "chemical analysis",
        question: "Which of the following is not a method of non-destructive testing of steel casting and forgings?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Energy lost due to turbulence and friction varies with kinetic energy.", "Reynolds number will be less than 2000.", "Pipe toughness affects the friction factor.", "The average velocity will be nearly the same as at the pipe center."],
        correctAnswer: "Reynolds number will be less than 2000.",
        question: "For turbulent flow of a fluid in a pipe, all of the following are true. EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["bending stress", "compressive stress", "shearing stress", "tensile stress"],
        correctAnswer: "shearing stress",
        question: "Structural steel elements subjected to torsion develop:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Electrons are minority carriers in the p - base region.", "Electrons are majority carriers in the n - emitter and n - collector regions.", "Holes are majority carriers in the p - base region.", "The emitter is positive with respect to the collector."],
        correctAnswer: "The emitter is positive with respect to the collector.",
        question: "When the emitter to base of an npn transistor is forward biased, and base to collector is reverse biased, all of the following are correct EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["plastic range", "elastic range", "modulus of elongation", "irreversible range"],
        correctAnswer: "elastic range",
        question: "The linear portion of the stress-strain diagram of steel is known as the:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["heat energy cannot be completely transfomed into work.", "energy can be neither created nor destroyed.", "internal energy is due to molecular motion.", "head can only be transferred from a body of higher temperature to one of lower temperature."],
        correctAnswer: "energy can be neither created nor destroyed.",
        question: "The first law of thermodynamics states that:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Metals are chemical elements that form substances that are opaque, lustrous, and good conductors of heat and electricity.", "Oxides, carbides, and nitrides are considered to be within the class of materials known as glasses.", "Ceramics are inorganic, nonmetallic solids that are processed or used at high temperature.", "Most metals are strong, ductile, and malleable. In general, they are heavier than most other substances."],
        correctAnswer: "Oxides, carbides, and nitrides are considered to be within the class of materials known as glasses.",
        question: "Which of the following statements is false?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["3", "4", "2", "5"],
        correctAnswer: "5",
        question: "How many significant digits do 10.097 have?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["alter the grain size of the metal", "intensifies deterioration temporarily", "inhibits further deterioration", "changes the composition of the metal"],
        correctAnswer: "inhibits further deterioration",
        question: "With regard to corrosion of metals, passivation is the process that:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["where the shearing stress is zero", "which are 45 degrees apart", "where the shearing stress is a maximum", "which are subjected only to tension"],
        correctAnswer: "where the shearing stress is zero",
        question: "Principal stresses occur on the planes:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["dS &amp;amp;gt; 0", "dS = dQ/T", "dS &amp;amp;lt; 0", "dS = 0"],
        correctAnswer: "dS &amp;amp;gt; 0",
        question: "For irreversible process, what is true about the total change in entropy of the system and surroundings?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["The atomic weight of Cs is larger", "Cs is too large to be coordinated by only 6 chloride ions.", "Cs contains more electrons than the weight of Na.", "Cs forms covalent bonds in CsCl"],
        correctAnswer: "Cs is too large to be coordinated by only 6 chloride ions.",
        question: "Cesium (Cs) and sodium (Na) both have the same valence (+1), yet with chlorine (Cl), cesium has a coordination number of 8 in CsCl, while sodium has coordination number of only 6 in NaCl. What is the main reason for this difference?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["body-centered cubic", "face-centered cubic", "simple cubic", "close-packed hexagonal"],
        correctAnswer: "face-centered cubic",
        question: "Which crystal structure possesses the highest number of close-packed planes and close-packed direction?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["q varies as (velocity, V)^2", "q varies approximately as (diameter, D)^2", "q decreases inversely as (fluid density, D)^1/2", "q decreases as pipe surface roughness ratio, E/D increases"],
        correctAnswer: "q varies as (velocity, V)^2",
        question: "At constant pressure P all of the following statements about low rate, Q in turbulent flow in a pipe are true, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["d = 2a/sqrt. ((1/h)^2 + (1/k)^2 + (1/l)^2)", "d = a (1/h + 1/k + 1/l)", "d = (a/2) sqrt. (h^2+k^2+l^2)", "d = a/sqrt. (h^2 + k^2 + l^2)"],
        correctAnswer: "d = a/sqrt. (h^2 + k^2 + l^2)",
        question: "Given that a is a lattice constant that h, k, and I are the Miller indices, which of the following equations describes the interplanar distance d in a cubic crystal?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Stay the same", "Increase and then decrease", "Decrease and then increase", "increase only"],
        correctAnswer: "increase only",
        question: "In any non-quasistatic thermodynamics process, the overall entropy of an isolated system will:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tc/Th-Tc", "1 - Tc/Th", "Th - Tc/Th", "Th/Tc"],
        correctAnswer: "Tc/Th-Tc",
        question: "A Carnot operates between two reservoirs. One reservoir is at a higher temperature, TH, and the other is a cooler temperature, Tc. What is the coefficient of performance, COP, of the refrigerator?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["pressure and velocity", "flow energy, kinetic energy, height above datum. and internal energy", "pressure density, velocity and height above datum", "pressure, density and velocity."],
        correctAnswer: "flow energy, kinetic energy, height above datum. and internal energy",
        question: "Total energy of a compressible or incompressible fluid flowing across any section in a pipeline is a function of:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Horsepower, P is increased by a factor of 8.", "Head, horsepower and volume flow rate are independently variable.", "Head, H is increased by a factor of 4.", "Volume flow rate, Q is increased by a factor of 2."],
        correctAnswer: "Head, horsepower and volume flow rate are independently variable.",
        question: "On doubling the speed, N, of centrfugal pump, all of the following are true, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["electrons with positive charge", "the K-quantum shell electrons", "the outershell electrons", "the electrons of the complete quantum shells"],
        correctAnswer: "the outershell electrons",
        question: "What are valence electrons?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["heat treatment of a low carbon steel.", "static pressure in a fluid becoming less than fluid vapor pressure.", "rivets under impact load.", "exposure of concrete to salt water."],
        correctAnswer: "static pressure in a fluid becoming less than fluid vapor pressure.",
        question: "Cavitation is the result of",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["directly proportional to the modulus of elasticity and moment of Inertia", "Inversely proportional to the weight and length", "inversely proportional to the modulus of elasticity and length of the beam cubed", "inversely proportional to the modulus of elasticity and moment of Inertia"],
        correctAnswer: "inversely proportional to the modulus of elasticity and moment of Inertia",
        question: "The deflection of a beam is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["It is always less than zero.", "It is always greater than zero.", "It is temperature-dependent.", "It is always zero."],
        correctAnswer: "It is always zero.",
        question: "During an adiabatic, Internally reversible process, what is true about the change in entropy?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["plastic", "metal", "rubber", "glass"],
        correctAnswer: "metal",
        question: "Which of the following is not a viscoelastic material?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["the hydraulic gradient", "friction head", "the energy gradient", "stagnation pressure"],
        correctAnswer: "the hydraulic gradient",
        question: "The locus of the elevations to which water will rise in piezometer tube is termed:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["sin B &amp;amp;gt; 0 and cos B &amp;amp;lt; 0", "sin B &amp;amp;lt; 0 and cos B &amp;amp;lt; 0", "sin b &amp;amp;lt; 0 and cos B &amp;amp;gt; 0", "sin B &amp;amp;gt; 0 and cos B &amp;amp;gt; 0"],
        correctAnswer: "sin b &amp;amp;lt; 0 and cos B &amp;amp;gt; 0",
        question: "Angles are measured from the positive horizontal axis, and the positive direction is counterclockwise. What are the values of sin B and cos B in the 4th quadrant?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["all adiabatic", "all isothermal", "two adiabatic and two isentropic", "two isothermal and two isentropic"],
        correctAnswer: "two isothermal and two isentropic",
        question: "The ideal, reversible Carnot cycle involves four basic processes. What type of processes are they?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Its deformation properties are more directional.", "Its stacking order is ABCABC.", "It has the closes packed lattice structure.", "Its coordination number is 2"],
        correctAnswer: "Its deformation properties are more directional.",
        question: "Comparing the face-centered cubic lattice with the hexagonal close-packed lattice, which of the following features describes the hexagonal close-packed structure only?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["defined as the length divided by the moment of inertia.", "defined as the unit shear stress divided by the unit shear deformation.", "a function of the length and depth", "equal to the modulus of elasticity divided by one plus Poisson&amp;amp;#39;s ratio."],
        correctAnswer: "defined as the unit shear stress divided by the unit shear deformation.",
        question: "The modulus of rigidity of a steel member is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["modulus of elasticity", "plastic range", "elastic range", "irreversible range"],
        correctAnswer: "elastic range",
        question: "The linear portion of the stress - strain diagram of steel is known as the:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["I and II in succession", "II and I in succession", "I only", "II only"],
        correctAnswer: "I only",
        question: "Which of the following set of reversible process describes an ideal Otto cycle?&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;I. adiabatic compression, isometric heat addition, adiabatic expansion, isometric heat rejection&amp;lt;BR/&amp;gt;II. isothermal compression, isobaric heat addition, isothermal expansion, isobaric heat rejection",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Energy loss varies as the square of the velocity", "Fluid particles move along smooth, straight paths", "Energy loss varies linearly with velocity", "Newton&amp;amp;#39;s law of viscosity governs the flow"],
        correctAnswer: "Energy loss varies as the square of the velocity",
        question: "Which of the following statements most nearly approximates conditions in turbulent flow?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["W/(delta)S", "W/(delta)S", "W - (delta)S", "(delta)S/W"],
        correctAnswer: "W/(delta)S",
        question: "What is the temperature difference of the cycle if the entropy difference is (delta)S, and the work done is W?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Use of a condensable vapor in the cycle increases the efficiency of the cycle.", "In practical terms, the susceptibility of the engine materials to corrosion is not a key limitation on the operating efficiency.", "Superheating increases the efficiency of a Rankine cycle.", "The temperatures at which energy is transferred to and from the working liquid are less separated than in a Carnot cycle."],
        correctAnswer: "In practical terms, the susceptibility of the engine materials to corrosion is not a key limitation on the operating efficiency.",
        question: "Which of the following statements regarding Rankine cycles is not true?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Ductility decreases", "Grains become equi-axed", "Tensile strength increases", "Recrystallization temperature decreases"],
        correctAnswer: "Grains become equi-axed",
        question: "When a metal is cold worked all of the following generally occur EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["volume flow rate", "kinetic energy", "pipe diameter", "friction factor"],
        correctAnswer: "kinetic energy",
        question: "Entrance losses between tank and pipe, or losses through elbows, fittings and valves are generally expressed as functions of ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["a measure of the deflection of a member", "a measure of a materials ability to store strain energy", "the reciprocal of the modulus of elasticity", "the same as the modulus of elasticity"],
        correctAnswer: "a measure of a materials ability to store strain energy",
        question: "Modulus of Resilience is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Longitudinal", "Circumferential", "Radial", "At an angle 45 degrees to the longitudinal and circumferential direction"],
        correctAnswer: "Circumferential",
        question: "A thin walled pressurized vessel consists of a right circular cylinder with flat ends. Midway between the ends the stress is greatest in what direction?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Work hardening by mechanical deformation below the recrystallization temperature (cold working)", "Heat treatment such as quenching and tempering, for production of a finer microstructure", "Precipitation processes, such as age hardening, which produce high strength by formation of sub microscopic phases during low temperature heat treatment", "Annealing above the recrystallization temperature"],
        correctAnswer: "Annealing above the recrystallization temperature",
        question: "All of the following processes strengthen metals, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["annealing", "work hardening", "quenching and tempering", "grain refinement"],
        correctAnswer: "annealing",
        question: "Steels can be strengthened by all off the following practices, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tetrafluoroethylene (Teflon) and other fluorocarbons", "Polyethylene, polypropylene, and polysterene", "Phenolics, melamine and epoxy", "Polyvinylchloride (PVC) and polyvinyl acetate"],
        correctAnswer: "Phenolics, melamine and epoxy",
        question: "All of the follwing groups of plastics are thermoplastic EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Fe^2+", "Fe", "Fe^3+", "They have the same radii."],
        correctAnswer: "Fe^3+",
        question: "Compare the metallic iron atom Fe and the ferric ions Fe^3+ and Fe^3+. Which has the smallest atomic results? (Assume all are at the same temperature.)",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Fourth", "Third", "Second", "First "],
        correctAnswer: "First ",
        question: "A vertically loaded beam, fixed at one end and simply supported at the other is indeterminate to what degree?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Linear defects, or slippage dislocations caused by shear", "ion pairs missing in ionic crystals (Shotky imperfections)", "lattice vacancies, or extra interstitial atoms", "displacement to form mirror images along a low energy boundary or crystal plane."],
        correctAnswer: "ion pairs missing in ionic crystals (Shotky imperfections)",
        question: "Imperfections within metallic crystal structures may be all of the following, EXCEPT:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["a measure of distance", "equal to the area of the cross section", "multiplied by the bending moment to determine the stress", "equal to the radius of gyration"],
        correctAnswer: "a measure of distance",
        question: "The ratio of the moment inertia of the cross section of a beam to the section modulus is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["turbulent", "dynamic", "laminar", "critical"],
        correctAnswer: "laminar",
        question: "In fluid flow, if the fluid travels parallel to the adjacent layers and the paths of individual particles do not cross, the flow is said to be:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
]